#Encodergasm Presents
～
Frozen, frozen, hard.
（エド）カチカチのコチ
No good after all...
（ジェット）やっぱり駄目だな
It's full of dioxins.
ダイオキシンばりばりだ
I had saved this as evidence a while back...
昔 証拠品として
保存しといたもんだが…
Don't eat it, you malnutritioned kid!!
食うな！ この欠食児童が！
Then you want to catch a fraud?  A matrimonial fraud?
（エド）じゃあ 詐欺 捕まえる？
結婚詐欺
Guess I have no choice.
（ジェット）しょうがねえ
What kinda fraud?  Is it big?
どんな詐欺？ おっきい？
Smallest of the small fry.
雑魚中の雑魚だ
スパイクは乗らねえだろうなあ
I don't think Spike will be up for this.
Ed wants chicken kabobs!
エドは焼き鳥ー
Guess I'll do it alone.
１人でやるか
（フェイの寝息）
You have GOT to be kidding!
（フェイ）冗談じゃないわよお！
ああ うう…
Give me a break...
勘弁してよ
うっ うう…
This stinks!
臭い！
Really...
（フェイ）全く　自分の尻は
自分で拭けって教わらなかった？
Weren't you taught that you should wipe your own butt?
I've been thinking of who you remind me of...
あんたって誰かに似てると
思ってたんだけど―
I know now.  That guy with the thin eyebrows...
あの男だわ　眉毛の薄いあいつ
Whitney Hagas Matsumoto.
ウィットニー･ハガス･マツモト
I wonder why I suddenly was reminded of him...
何で急に
あいつのこと 思い出したんだろ
誰も知らない私の過去
知りたい？
Do you want to know something about my past that nobody else knows?
Miss Manley, does she look resuscitated to you?
（バッカス）マンリー君 彼女は
生き返ったように見えるかね？
Yes, she does, Doctor.
（マンリー）
ええ 見えますわ ドクター
Miss Manley, does she look like an old woman to you?
（バッカス）マンリー君
彼女は ばあさんに見えるかね？
No, she doesn't, Doctor.
（マンリー）いいえ
見えませんわ ドクター
Do you think she has been successfully defrosted?
（バッカス）彼女は無事
解凍されたと思うかね？
I believe so, Doctor.
（マンリー）思います ドクター
Can you hear me?
分かるかね？ ヤッホー
I am Doctor Baccus.
私はドクター･バッカス
Baccus, as in the Baccus that drowned more humans than Neptune.
バッカスはネプチューンより
多くの人間を溺れさせた―
あのバッカスだ
Do you know about him?
知っとるかね？
But I used to be an alcoholic.  Baccus was drowning thanks to Baccus.
だが私は昔 アル中だった
バッカスが
バッカスに溺れたというわけだ
Hey, that was great!
こりゃ傑作だな ハーハハハハハハ
アッハッハッハッハ
All right, open wide...
はい お口を開けて
ふーん ふんふんふん
No problems.  You have no wounds left, and the cells are dividing nicely.
問題ない
傷も残ってないし
細胞も見事に分裂しとる
Now... you only have one problem to solve.
あとは ただ一つの問題を
クリアにすればいい
Oh, it's just a simple process.
何 簡単な手続きだ
The 30 million for the basic operation, and 54 years' worth of interest.
基本費用の3000万と
54年分の利息がついて―
えーと いくらだ？
Hey, how much is that?
273 million... add to that the hospital fees for a total of 300,028,000 woolongs.
２億7300万に
入院費を加算しまして―
全部で３億 飛んで飛んで
２万8000ウーロンです
Yes, if you pay up that much, you will be free.  Do you understand?
（バッカス）
そう それだけ払ってしまえば
もう自由だ　分かるね？
I don't understand...
（フェイ）分からない
Yes, that's it...
（バッカス）そう それで…
WHAT?!
何ですと？
Where is this?
ここは どこ？
Who am I?
私は誰？
フフハハハハハハハハハハッ
Miss Manley?
マンリー君
She is not acting, Doctor.
演技では ありませんわ ドクター
（ウィットニー）
弁護士のウィットニー･
ハガス･マツモトです
I am Whitney Hagas Matsumoto, your lawyer.
Lawyer?
弁護士？
（ウィットニー）
トータス保険会社に
依頼を受けまして―
At the request of the Totus Insurance Company, I did some research on your past.
あなたの過去について
いろいろ調査させていただきました
ミス･フェイ･ヴァレンタイン
Miss Faye Valentine.
Is that really my name?
それ 本当に私の名前？
すてきな名前じゃないですか
あなたによく似合う
It's a lovely name.
It suits you very well.
...and?
それで？
How much of your memory do you still have?
（ウィットニー）
ご記憶のほうは どの程度？
（フェイ）ああ… これはテレビ
This is a TV...
...this is a hot water pot...
これはポット
それから これは携帯電話
...and this is a cellular phone.
I know everything...
何でも分かってるわ
私 以外のことなら
...except about myself.
I see.
なるほど
And?
（フェイ）それで？
According to the materials that remain, when you were 20...
残された資料によると
あなたは二十歳のとき…
...well, you are still 20...
いや 今も二十歳なんですが
大変な事故に巻き込まれたようです
...you seem to have been involved in a serious accident.
事故？
Accident?
Such that medical technology back then could not completely cure you.
（ウィットニー）
当時の医療技術では
手の施しようのないほどの
I'm totally fine, as you can see.
こんなに全然 何でもないじゃない
どこにも傷一つ…
Not a scratch on my body.
Wait, what do you mean, "back then"?
当時って どういうこと？
今から54年前のことです
That was 54 years ago.
あっ…
You have been in cold-sleep, or rather cryogenically preserved, to this day.
あなたは この時代まで
コールドスリープ…
つまり冷凍保存されていたんです
And you were able to reawaken now that you could get the treatment you needed.
そして しかるべき処置が取れる
今になって―
やっと目覚めることができた
まるでスリーピング
ビューティーのように
Just like Sleeping Beauty.
You're kidding, right?
ふざけてんの？
真面目な話です
I am being serious.
Then this is a dream...
じゃあ夢だわ
No, it is definitely 2068 now.
（ウィットニー）
今は間違いなく2068年です
And this isn't a TV...
それから さっきのこれは
テレビではなく洗濯機です
...but a washing machine.
And this isn't a hot water pot...
こっちはポットではなく
自動洗顔機
...but an automatic face-washing machine.
それから これは電話ではなく
体温計です
And this is not a telephone, but a thermometer.
この丸い所を口に…
You put this round segment in your mouth...
（フェイ）ばかにしないでよ！
Don't mock me!
いきなり そんなこと言われたって
信用できる…
You just start saying stuff like that, and you expect me to believe...
Body temperature: 34.5 degrees Celsius.  Pulse: 54.  Blood pressure: 40/75.
（体温計）体温34.5度
脈拍54　血圧40から75
Still low.
まだ低い
Wait a minute!
ちょっと
Your memories end back when cellular telephones still looked like this.
あなたの記憶は―
携帯電話がこんな形だった時代で
止まってるんです
Then tell me!
じゃあ 教えてよ！
事故ってどんな？
What kind of accident?!  What was I like before then?!
その前の私は？ 私は何者なの？
Who am I?!
Calm down.  If you get excited, you...
落ち着いて　興奮すると君は…
What?!  What is going to happen...
何よ　どうなるっていうの？
You'll get sleepy.
眠くなるんですよ
Would you like one?
おひとつ いかが？
アッハハハハハハハ
Hey!
おーい　おーい　おーい
Hey!!
HEY!!
おー… あっ
はっ 待ってよ！
W-Wait!
（荒い息）
ミス･ヴァレンタイン
Miss Valentine!
Wait!
（ウィットニー）待ちなさい
Don't get near me!
来ないで！
逃げて どうなるんです？
What can you do by running away?!
はあ　ミス･ヴァレンタイン
Miss Valentine...
I can't pay 300 million...
（フェイ）３億なんて払えない
It's unreasonable for them to choose to resuscitate me...
勝手に生き返らせて
借金 払えなんて不条理よ
...and then expect me to pay the debt.
I don't even know anything about myself.
自分のこと 何も分からないで―
What should I do?
私 どうすればいいのよ
We can take it slow about the debt.
借金のことは
ゆっくり考えましょう
僕が力になりますから
I will help you.
記憶だって
いつか戻るかもしれませんよ
Your memory might come back to you someday.
生きていれば すてきな
出会いだって あるかもしれない
If you keep living, you might meet someone wonderful.
これ 何？
What... is this?
An ID.
ＩＤです
これで自分が死んでも忘れても―
This way, if you die, or if you forget yourself...
...they will know who you are and where you're from.
どこの誰か
分かるようになってるんです
And I don't have that...
私には ないのよね
What?!
何？
The collection agency!
取り立て屋だ
保険会社が業を煮やしたんだ
The insurance company got impatient!
What are we going to do?!
どうするの？
At this rate, we're both doomed.
このままじゃ ２人ともやられる
君は降りて走れ
You should get out of the car and run.
What about you?
あなたは？
We'll meet up at the Doctor's place.  All right?
（ウィットニー）
ドクターの所で落ち合おう
いいね？
Why are you helping me?
どうして私を助けてくれるの？
The prince must protect his sleeping beauty.
スリーピングビューティーは
王子様が守らなきゃな
～
手続きを したばかりだった
We just went through the paperwork.
He told us to hand you all of his assets if something happened to him.
自分に何かあったときには
君に全ての財産を譲渡するようにね
If you give us a thumbprint here, everything he owns will be yours.
ここに母印を押しさえすれば
彼の遺産は全て 君のものになる
ウィットニー 本当に私のことを…
Whitney...
You really cared for me...
さあ ここに指を
Now, put your thumb here.
文字が赤いのはなぜ？
Why are the numbers all red?
ううーん 借金も
財産のうちということだな
Well, they say that debt is an asset...
Debt...
借金？
You have GOT to be kidding!
冗談じゃないわよー！
I was stupid back then, now that I think about it.
（フェイ）
今 思えば ばかよね
I mean, he risked his life to save me.
あの人は私を助けるために
命を懸けたんだもの
His debt was nothing compared to mine.
借金だって私のに比べれば
すずめの涙
大した額じゃなかったのにね
It really wasn't that much.
You were there the whole time?
あんた ずっと そこにいたの？
Your story was way too long.
（スパイク）話が長すぎるんだよ
（スパイク）あきれた女だな
You are a horrible woman.
その相手も
今頃 あの世で嘆いてるぜ
I'm sure that guy is weeping in the afterlife...
...now that you ran away without paying the debt.
借金 放って逃げられたんじゃな
I can't help it.  It's not a sum that I can pay off.
しょうがないわ
払える額じゃないんだもん
開き直ってやがる
Now you're being defiant about it.
I've got some nerve, alright...  I'm much older than you are.
ずぶとくもなりますの
大年増ですから
Your past is all lies.  What was that about Romani?
（スパイク）
お前の過去は うそばっかだな
ロマニーだの何だの
Did you make this story up, too?
今のも作り話じゃないだろうな
It's neither a lie, nor a fake.
うそでも偽物でもないわ
本当のことが分からないだけよ
I just don't know the truth.
Like I can help it.
しょうがないじゃない
Welcome back!
おかえりなさーい
This guy is known as the "Madam Killer."
（ジェット）
こいつは通称 マダムキラー
ま せこい結婚詐欺師だがな
Well, he's just a cheap matrimonial fraud...
見えねえなあ
Sure doesn't look like one.
Well, I can do a good job even by myself.
（ジェット）ま 俺一人だって
十分 いい仕事をするのさ
Got that?
分かったろ？
Whitney Hagas Matsumoto...
（フェイ）
ウィットニー･ハガス･マツモト
いやー 久しぶり
H-Hey... long time no see...
What kinda relationship do they have that she wants to talk to him alone?
（ジェット）
２人っきりで話したいなんて
どういう関係だ？
ディープな関係らしいぜ
Apparently it's a pretty deep relationship.
An old guy of hers?
昔の男か？
お似合いのカップルだな
They were made for each other.
You seem very, VERY well, Mister Lawyer.
（フェイ）めちゃめちゃ元気そうね
弁護士さん
Is it because I'm fat?  Isn't that a biased opinion?
太ってるからか？ 偏見だな
I demand an explanation.
説明してほしいわ
脂肪注入したんだ
I got a fat implant after that accident.
あの事故の後―
Got a little incision around the armpit, and had it squeezed in...
この脇の下あたりを切って
ここから…
NOT THAT!
（フェイ）そうじゃない！
３年ぶりか
君が元気そうでよかった
It's been three years?
You look healthy, I'm glad.
Yeah, I'm sure you are.
よく言うわよ　あなたはそれで
生まれ変わったつもり？
Did you think that you completely reinvented yourself by doing that?
I wanted to start over...
やり直したかったんだ　何もかも
...start everything over.
And so you went with matrimonial fraud.
（フェイ）で 結婚詐欺師？
To think you're a bounty hunter...  This must have been destined.
君が賞金稼ぎとは　これも縁かな
So everyone was in on it?
（フェイ）
みんなグルだったってわけ？
Back then, I couldn't do anything else.  Because he sheltered me, the doctor.
（ウィットニー）
あのときは仕方なかったんだ
僕をかくまったばかりに
ドクターは…
捕まってよかったのかもしれないな
Maybe it was better to have been caught.
I couldn't wish for anything more than having you hand me over to the police.
君の手で警察に渡されるんなら
本望だ
You think it's all right to leave them alone?
（ジェット）
大丈夫かね？ ほっといて
女が心配か？
You worried about her?
I just thought that she might let him go.
やつを逃がすんじゃないかと
思っただけだ
Does she have that much sympathy in her heart?
そんな情のある女か？
Women as insistent as her tend to be the ones...
ああいう
突っ張らかってる女に限って―
...who get emotionally swayed by their exes.
ころっと昔の男なんてのに
流されるもんだ
Is that so?
そうかねえ
Women don't work on reason.
理屈じゃねえよ 女ってのは
Welcome, visitors!
お客さーん いらっしゃーい
So are you the ones that reported to us?
（バッカス）
通報してきたのは君たちかね？
Yeah, I want to claim a bounty.
（ジェット）ああ 賞金首を
引き渡したいんだ
I see.
（バッカス）なるほど
Miss Manley, prepare to rendezvous.
マンリー君 接舷準備
Yes, Inspector.
はい 警部
最後に会えてうれしかったよ
I'm glad I was able to meet you one last time.
元気で
Take care...
あえっ？
渡さないわ
I won't hand you over to them!
It's all right.
いいんだよ
僕のことならいいんだって！
You really don't have to mind me!
（ジェット）なんだ？
Are they ready to depart already?
（スパイク）もう出るつもりか？
Is she gonna let him go?
逃がす気か？
逃げる気かもな
She might be letting him go.
You wanna bet?
賭けるか？
分け前 ロクヨンだ
We're splitting it 60-40.
Dammit, hurry up, Spike!
（ジェット）急げよ！ スパイク
I'm trying!
（スパイク）やってるよ！
I-It's impossible...
なっ む 無理だよ
これに２人 乗るなんて
...to get both of us in this!
I don't care.
（フェイ）いいから
もっと息 吐いて　吐いて！
Breathe out some more!  EXHALE!
Hey, wait!
（ジェット）おい 待て！
I'm not letting you have him!
この人は渡さないわ
金より男を取ったぞ
She took the guy and not the money!
Jet captured him!
そいつはジェットが捕まえたんだ
I have to repay my debt to him.
私は この人に貸しがあるの
So I have the right to do what I want with him, and the bounty on him!
だから賞金も彼をどうするかも
私に権利があるの
Amazing.  She clearly states a pointless argument.
すげえ へりくつを
きっぱりと言い切ったな
だから言ったろ？
理屈じゃねえんだ 女は
That's what I told you.  Women don't work on reason.
Get me off this thing!
（ウィットニー）出してくれー
Are you gonna let him go?
（スパイク）そいつを逃がすのか？
We'll see!
（フェイ）さあね
お客さーん お疲れさーん
Visitor, thanks for coming!
Where are you going?
（ウィットニー）どこへ行くんだ？
What are you going to do with me?
僕をどうするつもりだ？
（フェイ）本当のことを教えて
I want you to tell me the truth.
Why was I there?
私は どうして あそこにいたの？
何が本当で
どこからが うそなの？
Where does the truth end, and where do the lies start?
What are you doing?!
何すんのよ
下手に動くとポッドに当たるぞ
If you're not careful, I'll hit the pod.
加減しないわよ
I'm not going to be easy on you!
That's MY line!
こっちのせりふだ
手間かけさせやがって
You're causing me a lot of trouble...
（フェイ）私は誰なの？
Who am I?
Do you really want to know your own past?
君は本当に
自分の過去を知りたいのかい？
Are you prepared for the consequences?
その覚悟が 君にあるのかい？
I am!
あるわ
そうか
I see...
Wait a minute.
（フェイ）ちょっと！
Well, I don't really know myself.
いや 僕は知らないんだけどね
You're so...
あんたねえ
Who you really are, where you are from, and where you will go.
（バッカス）自分が何者か
どこから来て どこへ行くのか
That is a question that every human asks himself at least once in his life.
人類 誰しもが
一度は思い悩む問いかけだ
And who are you?
誰よ
However, puberty is the only time you need to worry about things like that.
（バッカス）
だが そんなことは思春期に悩めば
もう十分だ
Only bored individuals think such thoughts after a certain age.
いい年になって考えてるのは
ただの暇人だな
I've heard that voice before...
どっかで聞いたことある声ね
Can you see me?
（バッカス）
見えるかね？ ヤッホー
Is that... the doctor and the nurse?
あれ ドクターと看護婦じゃない
Seems... that way.
そうみたいだね
Didn't you say something like that doctor passed away?
あんた ドクターは
死んだみたいなこと！
No, no...  I didn't mean it THAT way...
いや 違う 違う
そういう意味じゃなくて…
YOU!  How many lies do you have to tell before you're satisfied?!
あんた 一体どこまで
うそつけば気が済むの？
Um...  Er...
いや あの…
You were cryogenically preserved there.
（バッカス）君は あそこに
冷凍保存されていた
That we are certain of.  I guarantee it.
（バッカス）それだけは確かだ
私が保証しよう
私の過去は？ 私は一体？
What about my past?
Who in the world am I?
I gave you the name Valentine.
（バッカス）
ヴァレンタインという名は
私がつけた
私の好きな歌に ちなんでね
I named you after my favorite song.
As for everything else, all data was lost back in that Gate accident.
あとはゲート事故のときに
データが消失して―
分からんのだ
So I don't know who you are, or why you were put in cold-sleep...
誰が なぜ 君を
コールドスリープさせたのかもね
警察じゃなかったのか？
He wasn't a cop?
（パトカーのサイレン）
The patrol ship over there.  State your department.
（警察）そこのパトシップ
所属を述べなさい
I repeat.  The patrol ship over there.
繰り返す　そこのパトシップ
所属と登録ナンバーを明示しなさい
State your department and registration number.
Doctor... at this rate, we will be apprehended.
ドクター このままでは
私たちが捕まりますわ
It's truly unfortunate, but it's best that we not meddle in this any longer.
ああー 実に残念だが
これ以上は関わらんほうがいいな
Let's give up.
諦めましょう
So, farewell, Whitney.  Take care of yourself.
（バッカス）じゃ さらばだ
ウィットニー 元気でな
We're sorry!
（マンリー）ごめんなさいねえ
あ あれ？ ちょっと おじさん？
おじさーん！
H-Hey, wait!  Uncle!  UNCLE!
おじさん？
Uncle?
（ウィットニー）ああっ
今すぐ賞金と交換してやるわ
I'll take my bounty here and now!
There ya go!
そうこなくっちゃ
Good riddance.
いい気味ね
I guess you're getting paid back for all the lies that you told.
うそばかりついてた罰が
当たったってとこかしら？
There is one truth that I have spoken.
本当のことが一つある
眠ってる君に恋したことさ
That I fell in love with you while you were asleep...
...in love with a sleeping beauty.
スリーピングビューティーにね
いや うそ！
No, just kidding!
I'm lying!  It's a lie!
うそ うそだよ
Did you want me to come back that badly?
そんなに私に
帰ってきてほしかった？
You sure got a big mouth.
よく言うぜ
You were jealous.
やけたくせに
You really are a heartless woman.
（スパイク）
お前 つくづく薄情な女だよ
I guess I don't know anything about my past anymore...
私の過去 なあんにも
分かんなくなっちゃったな
Isn't that something that really doesn't matter?
どうでも いいことじゃねえのか？
あんたは過去があるから
そう思うのよ
You think that way because you have a past.
No matter the past, you still have a future.
（スパイク）過去はどうあれ
未来はあるだろ？
これは？
What's this?
Your share... of the 19,800 on his head.
（スパイク）お前の取り分だ
賞金１万9800のな
19,800?
（フェイ）１万9800？
（スパイク）雑魚中の雑魚だからな
The smallest of the small fry.
It wasn't 198,000?
19万8000じゃなかったのか
I put an extra digit in there...
１桁 間違ってたわ
Too much time has passed by...
Aishiteta to nageku niwa
...to lament that we were deeply in love.
Amarinimo toki wa sugite shimatta
The wind keeps blowing, while my heart...
Mada kokoro no hokorobi wo
...cannot heal all the tears in it.
lyasenu mama kaze ga fuiteru
Someone, cry for me with parched eyes.
Kawaita hitomi de dareka naite kure
The real folk blues.
The real folk blues
I only want to know what true sadness is.
Honto no kanashimi ga shiritai dake
Sitting in muddy water...
Doro no kawa ni tsukatta
...isn't such a bad life...
Jinsei mo waruku wa nai
...if it ends after the first time...
Ichido kiri de owaru nara
～
So, the next episode of Cowboy Bebop...
（ジェット）
さて 次回のカウボーイビバップは
はっきり言って暗い
...I admit, is really heavy and depressing.
そして重い
出てくるのは いい年こいた
汗臭い男ばかり
The only people that show up are well-aged, musty men.
言いたかないが地味だ
I hate to say this, but it is rather lackluster.
Children shouldn't watch it.
子供は見ないほうがいいだろう
女性も よしたほうがいい
Ladies should avoid it, too.
And to top it off, it's better for young guys to not watch either.
それに 若い男も
見ないほうが賢明だ
次回
「ブラック･ドッグ･セレナーデ」
Next episode: Black Dog Serenade.
おい おやじだけは―
Just to all the old guys... make sure you watch it.
見てくれ